Soto Hernandez Senior Full Stack Engineer

💌 sotohndz821@outlook.com 📞 +1 (435) 363-9580 👂 New Port Richey, FL

Profile

Persistent professional equipped with 15+ years of comprehensive experience in Software Development industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Experienced with the full software development lifecycle from planning to launch. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions and global project management. A big fan of basketball and e-sports. A self-motivated, avid learner

Professional Experience

Tech Lead April 2020 - Present

Permohil

- Led the engineering team with **10+** engineers to create platform for authors.
- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually using Javascript, Typescript, PHP, RoR, Elixir, MySQL, Oracle, React, Node.js, Next.js and Golang, gRPC.
- Responsible for the DevOps role using **GCP**, **AWS**, **Kubernetes** and **Docker**.
- Reduced response time and bundle size of **React** and **Angular** application by 50%.
- Experienced in leveraging Java and ColdFusion for dynamic and scalable web application development.
- Developed and executed **Selenium** automated tests, enhancing product reliability and release efficiency.
- Created **Google AMP** version of websites to achieve faster loads in mobile devices.
- Prototyped the **pixel perfect design** with frontend developers.
- Created microservices using AWS lambda, DynamoDB, Landing Zone Accelerator and S3.
- Created restaurant mobile application for iOS and Android using React Native.
- Worked on fun mobile application which turns any **iOS** device into musical instrument.
- Created Desktop App for editing Music files using **React**, **PostgreSQL** and **Node.js**.
- Got better sense of how to use **Agile approaches** properly.
- Trained team members in successful strategies to meet product goals.

Senior Full Stack Engineer

May 2016 - April 2020

Toptal

- Leading the conversion of the old **Angular** application to a new **React** app.
- Customized the **Drupal** plugins and themes.
- · Developed and maintained web applications for internal teams built with Javascript, PHP, Elixir, MongoDB, React and Typescript, Node.js, Golang, RoR.
- · Designed and implemented a flexible React UI framework that allowed the team to rapidly develop experiences that changed based on user authorizations.
- Utilized **Selenium** for automated testing, resulting in improved product quality and faster releases.
- Developed a NodeJS and Typescript development proxy service that enables new team members to setup a development environment in minutes rather than hours.
- Developed serverless web applications with AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, AWS S3, AWS SNS, Landing Zone **Accelerator** and so on.
- Worked on fun mobile application which turns any **iOS** device into musical instrument.
- Created Android version of existing **iOS** app.

• Created the Desktop App for browsing AWS S3 files using **Electron**.

Senior Software Engineer

April 2013 - May 2016

Mxicoders

- Participated in development and maintain of ecommerce websites using Javascript, Typescript, PHP, Elixir, Laravel, RoR, Golang, gRPC, Node.js, MySQL, Oracle, jQuery and React.
- Developed 200+ unit tests to verify the functionality of user interfaces, back-end processing, connectivity, and relational database interactions using **MySQL**.
- Worked on fun mobile application which turns any **iOS** device into musical instrument.
- Deeply dived into modification and improvement of built-in sound engine by utilizing MIDI technology.
- Achieved higher **UX** level by adding relevant animations and improving handle of user interactions.
- Created Android version of existing **iOS** app
- Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Mentored junior members and delivered training to boost team skills set.

Software Engineer May 2009 – April 2013

Mxicoders

- Developed a new-generation task management platform using PHP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- Built the several school websites using **Drupal and WordPress**.
- Utilized my JavaScript knowledge to improve an existing musicians' collaboration platform.
- Integrated third-party tools and components into applications.
- Cooperated with the UX department to create a new look and feel for the website, implemented changes with jQuery library extensions, Ajax & CSS.
- Promoted experience with Amazon Web Services and Agile Methodology.

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science

September 2008 - May 2009 | Stockton, CA

Stockton University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

June 2005 – May 2008 | Stockton, CA

Stockton University

Skills

Programming Languages (C#, Java, PHP, Python, JS, TS, Python, Golang)

Frontend Engineering (HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, tailwindCSS, Vue, Nuxt, React, Angular, Next)

Backend Engineering (.NET, Spring Boot, Laravel, Node.js, Express, Nest, Django, Golang)

Database Management (SQL - MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle NoSQL - MongoDB, Redis)

Testing Frameworks (Jest, Cypress, Mocha, JUnit, PyUnit, Enzyme)

DevOps Engineering (AWS, Azure, Docker, Kubernets, Jenkins, CircleCI, Ansible, Terraform)

Agile Methodologies (Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Asana, Trello)